# **KOITHENG PK NGWASHENG**

Final Year BSc Information Technology Student

2377 Lekoko Street, Middelburg, MP | +27 78 171 2249 | Ngwasheng113055@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

My academic background led me to an interest in IT auditing and cybersecurity, equipped with me hands-on experience in system development, risk assessment, and data analysis. I am keen on assessing IT systems and controls by identifying potential risks, evaluating compliance with security policies, and recommending improvements to enhance data integrity, operational efficiency, and regulatory compliance

## **EDUCATION**

# **North West University**

2022 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Golden Key Member est. 2023

# **Relevant Coursework and Projects**

## CMPG 223: Systems Analysis and Design

 Applied system design and implementation, project management, creative problem-solving, teamwork, and ethical use of computing resources in the development of real-world computerised systems.

## **CMPG 215: Information Security**

 Gained practical knowledge in safeguarding digital assets, applying cybersecurity principles, ethical data handling, and implementing access control, risk management, and security policies.

## **CMPG 322: Decision Support Systems**

 Developed decision-making models using quantitative analysis, statistical tools, and datadriven techniques to support business problem-solving and strategic planning

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **North West University**

## Statistics 1 Supplementary Instructor

July 2022 - Nov 2022

- Provide supplementary assistance to students
- Assist the lecturer with lesson facilitation
- Provide extra tutoring for students

#### **North West University**

#### **Marking Assistant**

July 2024 - Nov 2024

- Assist the lecturer with marking students' C# program activities
- Provide constructive feedback to students on activities
- · Assist students during in-class practical sessions

#### SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Programming Languages: C# (.NET Framework), Python, C++, Java
- Database Management: SQL, mySQL, Oracle
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- Report Writing
- Written and Verbal Communication